Let's try to understand a little better how uniform cost search works.
我们来进一步了解一致代价搜索的原理
We started on start state, and
先从初始状态开始
then we start expanding out from there looking at different paths.
从该状态开始拓展 观察不同的路径
And what we end up doing is expanding
最后的效果就是
in terms of contours like on a topological map.
我们按拓扑地图那样的轮廓进行了拓展
Where first we expand out to a certain distance,
也就是先扩展到一定的距离
then to a farther distance and then to a farther distance.
然后拓展得更远些 之后再远些
Now, at some point, we meet up with the goal.
到了某个时候 我们就会找到目标
Let's say the goal is here.
假设目标在这里
Now, we found a path from the start to the goal.
现在我们找到了一条从初始状态出发、通往该目标的路径
But notice that the search really wasn't directed at any way towards the goal.
但注意搜索并没有直接指向目标
It was expanding out everywhere in this space.
而是在空间里向四面八方拓展
And depending on where the goal is, we should expect to have to explore half of
根据目标所处的位置
the space on average before we find the goal.
预计我们平均需要探索一半的空间才能找出目标
If the space this small, that can be fine.
如果空间不大 那就还好
But when spaces are large, that won't get us to the goal fast enough.
但如果空间很大 那我们就没办法很快地找到目标了
Unfortunately, there's really nothing we
遗憾的是 我们做不了什么
can do with what we know to do better than that.
只凭现在知道的信息 我们做不到更好了
And so if we want to improve, if we want to be able to find the goal faster,
所以如果我们想改善算法 想更快地找出目标
we're going to have to add more knowledge.
我们就需要更多的信息
The type of knowledge that's proven most useful,
而经证明 最有用的搜索信息
in search is an estimate of the distance from the start state to the goal.
是初始状态与目标之间的预测距离
So let's say we're dealing with a route finding problem,
假设我们面对的是路径寻找问题
and we can move in any direction, up or down, right or left.
我们可以向任意方向移动 上下左右均可
And we'll take as our estimate,
所以我们取
the straight line distance between a state and goal.
状态与目标之间的直线距离作为预测值
And we'll try to use that estimate to find our way to the goal fastest.
我们要试着用这个预测值 以最快的速度找出通往目标的路径
Now, an algorithm called greedy best-first search does exactly that.
现在 有个叫贪婪最佳优先搜索的算法就能做到这一点
It expands first the path that's closest to the goal according to the estimate.
它会根据预测值 优先扩展距离目标最近的路径
So what are the contours look like in this approach?
所以这个算法的轮廓是怎样的呢？
Well, we start here, and then we look at all the neighboring states.
我们从这里开始 观察所有相邻状态
And the ones that appear to be closest to the goal, we would expand first.
优先扩展那些看起来离目标最近的状态
So we'd start expanding like this and like this, and like this,
所以我们会像这样、这样、这样
and like this, and that would lead us directly to the goal.
和这样进行拓展 这样我们就能直接朝目标前进了
So now, instead of exploring whole circles that go out everywhere in
所以现在在搜索空间里 我们不朝四面八方搜索了 搜索轮廓也不是圆圈
the search space, our search is directed towards the goal.
我们的搜索会朝目标扩展
In this case, it gets us immediately towards the goal.
因此 我们能够马上朝目标移动
But that won't always be the case if there are obstacles along the way.
但如果中间有障碍的话 情况又不一样了
Consider this search space, we have a start state and a goal.
假设这个搜索空间里有一个初始状态和一个目标
And there's an impassable barrier.
中间有一个无法跨越的障碍
Now a greedy best-first search will start expanding out as before,
贪婪最佳优先搜索一开始会像之前一样扩展
trying to get towards the goal.
试着抵达这个目标
And when it reaches the barrier, what will it do next?
等它到达障碍处 它会怎么做呢？
Well, it will try to increase along a path that's getting closer and
它会沿着某一路径继续扩展 慢慢地接近
closer to the goal.
目标
So it won't consider going back this way, which is farther from the goal.
所以它不会考虑折返到这里 这样离目标的距离较远
Rather, it will continue expanding out along this lines,
而是会沿着这条线继续扩展
which always get closer and closer to the goal, and
这样就总是能慢慢接近目标
eventually will find its way towards the goal.
并在最后找到通往目标的路径了
So does find the path, and it does it by expanding a small number of nodes, but
所以算法会找出路径 为了找出路径 它会扩展少数 点
it's willing to accept a path which is longer than other paths.
但它能够接受比其它路径长的路径
Now if we can explore it in the other direction,
如果我们反方向进行拓展
we could have found a much simpler path, a much shorter path,
就会找到一条简单许多也短许多的路径
by just popping over the barrier and then going directly to the goal.
只要直接跳过障碍就能直通目标了
But greedy best-first search wouldn't have done that because that would have
但贪婪最佳优先搜索不会这么做
involved getting to this point, which is this distance from the goal, and
因为这么做就得到这里 离目标还有这么远
then considering states which were farther from the goal.
所以它会考虑实际上离目标更远的状态
What we would really like is an algorithm that combines the best parts
我们真正想要的算法是要将贪婪搜索的精华
of greedy search, which explores a small number of nodes in many cases, and
也就是能在大多数情况下探索少数节点
uniform cost search, which is guaranteed to find the shortest path.
和一致代价搜索 也即保证能找到最短路径的算法结合起来
We'll show how to do that next using an algorithm called the A* algorithm.
接下来我们会讲如何实现这一点 我们要用一个叫做 A* 的算法
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[无声音]